temando.com 2019-02-03

# Privacy Policy | Temando

## About Temando

Temando is committed to protecting and respecting your privacy. Indeed, protecting your personal information is one of the key success criteria by which we measure our performance. 

The controller of data collected through this website ([www.temando.com)](http://www.temando.com%29/) or through business interactions with business customers, employment candidates, and vendors is Temando Holdings Pty Limited ACN 122 087 512, with subsidiary Temando Pty Limited ACN 120 582 738 (together, “Temando”). The website [www.temando.com](http://www.temando.com/), is owned and operated by Temando Pty Ltd (Site).

This Privacy Policy describes how Temando, as a controller of these data, collects, uses, shares and secures the personal information you provide. It also describes your choices and rights regarding your personal information.

Temando also operates Services for business Clients that have engaged us, and we work at the direction for those Clients as a processor. Though our Clients’ privacy policies apply to how we handle these Services data, this Privacy Policy also describes how users of our Clients’ services may make requests or ask questions regarding their personal information. 

## Questions or Complaints

If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy or practices, please contact us here or email us at  [privacy@temando.com](mailto:privacy@temando.com). We will review your question and respond to you within 30 days.  We aim to resolve all issues in a timely manner, or as mandated by local law, but if a more detailed investigation is required, we will keep in regular contact with you to ensure that you are kept informed of the resolution of your matter.

If you have an unresolved concern about your personal information that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at <https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request>.

### For European Union residents

If you are in the EU, and if you are not satisfied with our resolution of your complaint through our internal processes or our third-party dispute resolution service, you may complain to the Governing Data Protection Authority of your country of residence. We commit to cooperating with the panel established by the EU data protection authorities (DPAs) or the Swiss Federal Data Protection and Information Commissioner (FDPIC) and comply with the advice given by the panel or the FDPIC with regard to personal data transferred from the EU or Switzerland.

## Where We Keep and Access Your Data

Temando is a global company and may store and access your data around the world, including in countries other than your own. Regardless of the location, we maintain the same standards for securing and processing your personal information. Where required, we maintain standard contractual clauses to provide privacy adequacy for transfers of personal data outside of the European Union.

## How We Share Your Data

### With Third Party Providers

We may disclose your personal information to third parties who provide services to us, including related bodies corporate, affiliates, partners, carriers,, e-commerce platforms, contractors and third party services (“ **Temando Service Providers** ”) that assist us with our business activities _._  Some of these entities may be overseas including in Australia, United Kingdom, European Union, Singapore, Hong Kong, the Philippines Vietnam and New Zealand. Your information may be transferred internationally for the purposes of processing by Temando or Temando Service Providers. We require all third parties to respect the security of your personal data and to treat it in accordance with the law.

### For Legal Reasons

In certain situations, Temando may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements. Temando cooperates with law enforcement inquiries and other third parties to enforce laws, intellectual property infringements, to comply with a subpoena, bankruptcy proceedings, or similar legal process; and other rights. Your personal information may be disclosed when required to do so by law.  Local, and international law enforcement agents can request and may receive your personal information.

### Merger, Acquisition and Sale 

If Temando is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, your personal information may be disclosed to advisers, consultants and any third party involved in the transaction which will be subject to confidentiality obligations.   

## This Website and Our Offline Business Activities

### Information We Collect Directly

We collect personal information online via our website and also directly from you during the course of our business relationship.  Our main goal in collecting personal information from you is to provide you with a  **smooth, efficient, and personalized experience**  and maintain our business relationship with you. This allows us to provide services and features that most likely meet your needs, and to customize our service to make your experience easier and quicker. If you are communicating with us about open employment positions we might have, we use your personal information to evaluate possible career fits and communicate with you.

### Information We Collect Automatically

We automatically **  track certain information** about you based upon your online behavior on our website. We use this information to do **  internal research** on our users' demographics, interests, and behaviour to better understand and serve our users. This information is compiled and analysed on an  **aggregated basis**.

Technologies such as: COOKIES and similar technologies are used by Temando and our partners, Adroll, Google Analytics and Salesforce. These technologies are used in analyzing trends, administering the site, tracking users’ movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual as well as aggregated basis.

We use COOKIES for our shopping cart, to remember users’ settings (e.g. language preference), and for authentication. Users can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level. If you reject cookies, you may still use our site, but your ability to use some features or areas of our site may be limited.

As is true of most websites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information may include Internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and/or clickstream data to analyze trends in the aggregate and administer the site. We may combine this automatically collected log information with other personal information we collect about you. We do this to improve services we offer you and to improve site functionality.

We partner with a third party ad network to either display advertising on our Web site or to manage our advertising on other sites. Our ad network partner uses cookies and similar technologies to collect certain information about your activities on this and other Web sites to provide you targeted advertising based upon your interests.  If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you targeted ads, you may opt-out by clicking [Here](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/).  Please note this does not opt you out of being served advertising.  You will continue to receive generic ads.

### Children

We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 16.

### Surveys & Contests

From time-to-time our Site may request information from users via surveys, contests or for a particular service (e.g. newsletter). Participation in these surveys or contests is completely voluntary and the user therefore has a choice whether or not to disclose this information. Information requested will include contact information (as supplied to the site during registration) and supplementary information on your professional interests, opinions and preferences (e.g. choice of software, working practices, opinions on industry issues, feedback on the Temando web site). We will use the contact information to notify winners. We will not publish winners' details on the site though on request we will provide details of any winners' name and organisation. If the survey or contest has a sponsor then we will share information given by entrants with the sponsor.

If you do not provide the information requested you may not be eligible to participate in the contest or survey.

### Payment Processing

In order to process payments online we require the billing address for the credit card used and our external payment service provider, eWAY, requires your credit card details. For details of how your information is used, please see following section. If you do not provide this information we cannot process your payment. 

### Information We Collect Through Business Activities

Apart from collecting personal information via our website/s, we collect personal information from individuals that interact with our business.  This may be because you contact us with an enquiry, are looking for employment, are a business customer of ours, or are a service provider to our business.  We will generally only collect and hold information you have provided to us such as your name, telephone number and email address; and in the case of employment recruiting, information in your resume and employment application. We will use this information to deal with your enquiry, manage your account, pay you, assess your suitability for a position with us and otherwise fulfil your request and maintain our primary business relationship.  

We will only use the information provided for the purposes for which it was collected unless you consent to us using it for other purposes, except as you would reasonably expect us to use it for another purpose or as required by law. 

### Our Uses of Your Information

We use personal information about you for the following reasons:

  * to register you as a customer and manage our relationship with you;
  * to provide services through our Platform to our customers and end users;
  * to facilitate the provision of services through our Platform to our customers and end users by Temando Service Providers;
  * for the provision of customer or technical support to our customers and end users by Temando or Temando Service Providers;
  * to respond to your enquiries and requests, or investigate a complaint; 
  * to invoice, recover debts, and manage our business relationship; and
  * to assess your suitability for any job positions in which you have expressed an interest or may suit you. 

In addition to the uses described above, we use personal information about you to:

  * improve our marketing and promotional efforts; 
  * improve our systems, services, software or Platform. 
  * statistically analyse site usage;
  * improve our content and product offerings;
  * tailor our Site to users’ needs;
  * customise our site's content, layout, and services;

The above uses are necessary for the legitimate interests of gathering information for marketing, product and systems improvement, market analytics and the development of our business.

With your consent, we also use your  **e-mail address**  to send you newsletters, marketing and sales communications, or other communications (for example, digests of the forum posts) that you have requested from the Site. Out of respect for our users we offer an opt-out (see below).

We also use information from or about you, including information we obtain from your current and past activities on the Site, to resolve any disputes, prevent fraud, enhance security, troubleshoot problems and enforce our Master Services Agreement or Terms of Website. At times, we may look across multiple users to identify problems or resolve disputes, and in particular on rare occasions we may evaluate your information to look for users using multiple User IDs or alias.

We take online payments for our online freight quoting and booking service. We use eWAY as our external payment provider. In addition to the information outlined above, we require the billing address of the credit card you use so that we can pass this to eWAY who check the address against the cardholder's details for security purposes. eWAY requires that you provide your credit card details to process the transaction. This is done on a secure eWAY server using SSL (secure sockets layer). In the case of a suspected fraudulent transaction, Temando may be contacted for the sole purpose of performing further checks. These details are stored securely on an eWAY PCI Compliant (Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard) server in order to process future payments you may make, but eWAY does not use your information for any other purpose.

### Advertisers

We aggregate personal information and disclose such information in aggregate to advertisers and for other marketing and promotional purposes. However, in these situations, we do not disclose to these entities any information that could be used to personally identify you.

### Social Media Features and Widgets

Our Web site includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook button and Widgets, such as the Share this button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

### Links to Other Sites

Our Site contains links to other sites that are not owned or controlled by us. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites.  We encourage you to be aware when you leave our Site and to read the privacy policies of each and every Web site that collects personal information. 

### Single Sign-On

You can log in to our website using sign-in services such as Facebook Connect or an Open ID provider. These services will authenticate your identity, provide you the option to share certain personal information (such as your name and email address) with us, and to pre-populate our sign up form. Services like Facebook Connect give you the option to post information about your activities on this website to your profile page to share with others within your network.

### Control of Your Password

Except as specifically permitted by this section, **  you may not disclose** your Temando password to any third parties nor share it with any third parties. If you lose control of your password, you may lose substantial control over your personal information and may be subject to legally binding actions taken on your behalf. Therefore, if your password has been compromised for any reason, you should immediately change your password by visiting the preferences page on the Site.

You may, however, disclose your password to certain third parties with whom Temando has entered into specific contractual and technical arrangements designed to safeguard your password, in order to enjoy the benefits of those third parties' services in relation to the Temando services.

If you wish to change your password you can do so at any time by clicking on the 'change password' link located at the top of the page.

### Data Retention

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services or otherwise perform our business and legal obligations. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services, contact us as described below. 

## Your Rights and Information Choices

### Promotional communications

With your consent, we will periodically send you free newsletters and e-mails that directly promote the use of our site or the purchase of our products or services. When you receive newsletters or promotional communications from us, you may indicate a preference to stop receiving further communications from us – you will have the opportunity to “opt-out” by following the unsubscribe instructions provided in the e-mail you receive or by submitting a request at [unsubscribe](http://www2.temando.com/unsubscribe/u/86602)[. ](http://www2.temando.com/l/86602/2018-05-14/5fc53f)Should you decide to opt-out of receiving future mailings, we may share your e-mail address with third parties to ensure that you do not receive further communications from third parties. Despite your indicated marketing e-mail preferences, we may send you transactional emails and notices of any updates to our Terms of Service or Privacy Policy.

### Account or Profile Information

Upon request, Temando will provide you with information about whether we hold any of your personal data. You may ask us to update, correct or delete information about you at any time. If you wish to delete or suspend your account, please contact us, but note that we may retain certain information as required by law or for legitimate business purposes. Also, if you have become aware that a profile has been created about you without your consent or knowledge, you may contact us to request deletion of that said account.  We may also retain cached or archived copies of your information for a certain period of time. We will respond to your request without undue delay within 30 days.

You can also ask about:

•whether and why we have your personal data;  
•how we obtained your personal data;  
•what we have done with your personal data;  
•to whom we have communicated your personal data;  
•where your personal data has been stored, processed or transferred;  
•how long we will retain your personal data, or how that retention period will be determined; and  
•the safeguards in place to protect your information when it is transferred to third parties or third countries.  

Finally, you can ask us not to collect or use your personal data for certain purposes, you can ask us to delete your personal data, or you can ask us to either refrain from sharing your information with or specifically ask that we do provide your personal data to a third party.

Depending on which laws apply to your personal data, we may only be able to do some of these things for you. If you request one of these things and we refuse to do it, we will explain the reason for our refusal and any recourse you may have.

We will respond to your request without undue delay. We reserve the right to take reasonable steps to verify your identity prior to granting access or processing changes or corrections

To address any privacy or security questions or concerns, or to make any of these requests, contact us with details about your request at [privacy@temando.com](mailto:privacy@temando.com).

### Other Information Collectors

Except as otherwise expressly discussed in this Privacy Policy, this document only addresses the use and disclosure of information we collect from you. To the extent that you disclose your information to other parties, or other sites throughout the Internet, different rules may apply to their use or disclosure of the personal information you disclose to them.

### Security

In order to process and protect your credit card details, our payment provider eWAY uses SSL (secure sockets layer) encryption. The secure server is hosted by eWAY and not Temando.

We hold your information electronically on secure servers. We follow generally accepted standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it.  No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however.  Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. If you have any questions about security on our Site, you can contact us at [privacy@temando.com](mailto:privacy@temando.com). 

Some personal information may also be kept in hard copy form, such as business cards, invoices and personnel records.  Access to hard copies records is restricted.

## Information We Collect On Behalf of Our Clients

Where an organization (Client) uses Temando’s fulfilment software platform, Temando collects and processes personal information under the direction and on behalf of its Clients, and it has no direct relationship with the individuals whose personal data it processes. In these cases, Temando is a processor that works at its Clients’ direction and under the terms of its agreement, and the Clients’ privacy policies and terms apply. For example, Temando works with its Clients to help them provide notice to their customers concerning, the purpose for which personal information is collected.

If you are a customer of one of our Clients and would no longer like to be contacted by one of our Clients that use our service, please contact the Client with which you interact directly.  If you are a Client and would like to update your account you may do so by visiting the settings page on the site or by emailing us at [privacy@temando.com](mailto:privacy@temando.com). We may transfer personal information to Temando Service Providers that help us provide our service. Transfers to subsequent third parties are covered by the service agreements with our Clients or by agreements directly between our Clients and the relevant Temando Service Provider.

Temando acknowledges that you have the right to access your personal information. Temando has no direct relationship with the individuals whose personal data it processes. An individual who seeks access, who seeks to correct, amend, delete inaccurate data or withdraw consent to further contact should direct his/her query to Temando’s Client (the data controller). If the Client requests Temando to remove the data, we will respond to their request within 30 days. 

Temando will retain personal data we process on behalf of our Clients for as long as needed to provide services to our Client. We will retain and use this personal information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

### California Privacy Rights

If you are a user who resides in the State of California, you have the right to request from Temando a list of third parties with whom we share your PII for their own direct marketing purposes during the previous calendar year.  If you would like to request such information from us, please send an email  to us at [privacy@temando.com](mailto:privacy@temando.com) or at the following postal address: 550 Montgomery St. San Francisco, California 94111.

### Changes to Privacy Policy

We will update this Privacy Policy if our information handling practices change.  If we make any material changes we will publicize changes on our website or notify you by email (sent to the e-mail address specified in your account) prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

### **Contact Details**

Temando 

550 Montgomery Street

San Francisco CA 94111

Data Privacy Officer: Andrew McDonald 

Effective: 25 May, 2018
